FELIX.ACEVEDO.TECH@GMAIL.COM
HTTPS://FELIXA-GITHUB.GITHUB.IO/FIZZY-REACT-PORTFOLIO

FELIX ACEVEDO

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer leveraging a Physical Therapy background to build intuitive and responsive web experiences for all users. Relevant skills acquired at the UNCC-Coding Bootcamp, as well as Coursera and Treehouse. Transferable skills acquired through 10+ years of professional work as a Physical Therapist Assistant. Combined with an artistic eye and experience in creating art through Photoshop and with paint and canvas, I develop applications that are equally attractive on the front end and back end.

SKILLS

Relevant: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Web APIs, Third-Party APIs, Server-Side APIs, Node.js, Object Oriented Programming, Express.js, SQL, NoSQL, Model-View-Controllers, Bootstrap, JQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Handlebars, Insomnia, GraphQL, Heroku, Visual Studio, Object-Relational Mapping, Progressive Web Applications, and React.

Transferable: Team Collaboration and Contribution, Time Management, Critical Thinking, Communication, Customer Service, Case Management, Divergent Thinking, Perspective, Professional Documentation, Passion for Learning, and Staying up-to-date with Trends and Advancements within the Profession.

PROJECTS

Data Mammoth

GitHub: https://github.com/FelixA-GitHub/Data-Mammoth.git

Deploy: https://felixa-github.github.io/Data-Mammoth

- Project Summary A simple search engine for movies, with a favorites list.
- Responsibilities Repo setup, CSS, Coding for localStorage,
 Coding for API fetches.
- Tools/Languages JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Web APIs

RegalCare

GitHub: https://github.com/FelixA-GitHub/grasshopper-travel.git

Deploy: https://regal-care-inc.herokuapp.com

- Project Summary A website dedicated to traveling medical professionals whereby they can search and apply for short-term assignments in different cities. Employers can post, edit, and delete jobs as well.
- Responsibilities Repo setup, Seeding, Routes, Controllers,
 Connection, Authentication
- Tools/Languages JavaScript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, MySQL, Insomnia, Node.js

Grandma's Mismatched Taxidermy

GitHub:

https://github.com/FelixA-GitHub/Grandmas-Mismatched-Taxidermy

Deploy: https://infinite-falls-54621.herokuapp.com

- Project Summary A marketplace for taxidermy connoisseurs looking for flawed or mismatched taxidermy products to add to their collections.
- Responsibilities Repo setup, Setting up Client components/pages/utils/assets, Authentication, Bootstrap/CSS, MongoDB and Heroku setup/seeding/deployment
- Tools/Languages JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Heroku, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, Mongoose, React

EXPERIENCE

SAVASENIORCARE, Lincolnton, NC — Physical Therapist Assistant OCTOBER 2021 — PRESENT

- Daily scheduling, monitoring and kept an up-to-date calender of reassessment/recertification periods
- Charged with setup/maintenance/troubleshooting of tech equipment such as laptops, printers, and routers
- Communication via email/phone/Zoom with caregivers, MDs, and other disciplines involved.

Genesis Rehab, Charlotte, NC — Physical Therapist Assistant

JUNE 2021 - PRESENT

- Parkinson's Focused Specialty Training using the most up-to-date protocols and techniques
- Managed a personal caseload of 30-40 clients a week

SAVASENIORCARE, Seneca, SC - Physical Therapist Assistant

OCTOBER 2012 - JUNE 2021

- Professional documentation written utilizing documentation software such as Casamba and Rehab Optima
- Designed personalized exercise programs, taking into account multiple factors such as age/deconditioning/pain tolerance/weight/surgical precautions/contraindications
- Continuing Education Courses taken to acquire new skills, and keep up with current trends and advancements within the profession

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina at Charlotte — Certification

JANUARY 2022 - JULY 2022

Full Stack Developer Coding Bootcamp